vidhikarya.com 2017-10-09

# Privacypolicy

Effective Date: 25th February, 2016

VIDHIKARYA LEGAL SERVICES LLP. (“VIDHIKARYA”) provides this Privacy Policy to let you know our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information through www.VIDHIKARYA.com (the “Site”), and any other websites, features, applications, widgets or online services that are owned or controlled by VIDHIKARYA and that post a link to this Privacy Policy (together with the Site, the “Service”), as well as any information VIDHIKARYA collects offline in connection with the Service.

By accessing or using the Service, you consent to the information collection, disclosure and use practices described in this Privacy Policy. Kindy note that certain features or services referenced in this Privacy Policy may not be offered on the Service at all times. Please also review our Terms of Service, which governs your use of the Service, and which is accessible at https://www.VIDHIKARYA.com/info/terms/.

## 1\. INFORMATION COLLECTION

Users of the Service may be Clients (anyone utilizing the VIDHIKARYA platform to request services to be performed by a Lawyer) or Lawyers (any individual user, or groups of associated individual users or law firms utilizing the VIDHIKARYA platform to offer services to Clients). Information You Provide to Us

## Personal Information:

In the course of using the Service (whether as a Client or Lawyer), we may require or otherwise collect information that identifies you as a specific individual and can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Information”). Examples of Personal Information include your name, email address, postal address and phone number.

## Payment Information:

If you use the Service to make or receive payments, we will also collect certain payment information, such as credit card, other financial account information, and billing address.

## Identity Verification:

We may collect Personal Information, such as your date of birth, or taxpayer identification number (PAN), to validate your identity or as may be required by law, such as to complete tax filings. We may request documents to verify this information, such as a copy of your government-issued identification or photo or a billing statement.

## General Audience Service:

The Service is for general audience and intended for users 18 and older. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone younger than age 18. If we become aware that a child younger than 18 has provided us with Personal Information, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our files. If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child younger than age 18 and believe that VIDHIKARYA has collected Personal Information from your child, please contact us at: [info@VIDHIKARYA.com](mailto:info@VIDHIKARYA.com).

## Non-Identifying Information/Usernames:

We also may collect other information, such as zip/pin codes, demographic data, information regarding your use of the Service, and general project-related data (“Non-Identifying Information”). We may aggregate information collected from VIDHIKARYA registered and non-registered users (“VIDHIKARYA Users”). Usernames are made public through the Service and are viewable by other VIDHIKARYA Users.

## Information Collected from Users Automatically:

We and our third party service providers, including analytics and third party content providers, may automatically collect certain information from you whenever you access or interact with the Service. This information may include, among other information, the browser and operating system you are using, the URL or advertisement that referred you to the Service, the search terms you entered into a search engine that led you to the Service, areas within the Service that you visited, and other information commonly shared when browsers communicate with websites. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, and site functionality.

The information we collect also includes the Internet Protocol (“IP”) address or other unique device identifier (“Device Identifier”) for any device (computer, mobile phone, tablet, etc.) used to access the Service. A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned or connected to the device you use to access the Service, and our servers identify your device by its Device Identifier. Some mobile service providers may also provide us or our third party service providers with information regarding the physical location of the device used to access the Service.

## The technology used to collect information automatically from VIDHIKARYA Users may include the following:

## Cookies:

Like many websites, we and our marketing partners, affiliates, analytics, and service providers use “cookies” to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use both persistent cookies that remain on your computer or similar device (such as to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Service and to track your compliance with any VIDHIKARYA applicable policies) and session ID cookies, which expire at the end of your browser session (for example, to enable certain features of the Service, to better understand how VIDHIKARYA Users interact with the Service and to monitor aggregate usage by VIDHIKARYA Users and web traffic routing on the Service).

## Web Beacons:

We and our marketing partners, affiliates, analytics, and service providers may also employ software technology known as “web beacons” or “tracking tags” to help us keep track of what content on our Sites is effective and to serve relevant advertising to you. Web beacons are small graphics with a unique identifier that may be invisible to you, and which are used to track the online activity of Internet users. Web beacons are embedded in the web pages you review or email messages you receive. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to our Service, to monitor how VIDHIKARYA Users navigate the Service, to count how many emails that were sent were actually opened, or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

## Embedded Scripts:

An Embedded Script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Service, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your computer or other device and is deactivated or deleted when you disconnect from the Service. In addition, we may use a variety of other technologies that collect similar information for security and fraud detection purposes and we may use third parties to perform these services on our behalf.

## COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

## User Profiles:

You may have the opportunity to create a profile, which consists of information about you, and may include Personal Information, photographs, examples of your work, information on work previously performed via the Service and outside the Service, skills, hourly pay rates, feedback/rating information and other information, including your Profile. The information in your Profile may be visible to all VIDHIKARYA Users and the general public subject to the privacy choices you make within your VIDHIKARYA Profile. You may edit certain information in your Profile via your account and may choose to limit who is able to view certain content you post to your Profile. If in any case, you believe that an unauthorized profile has been created about you, you can request for it to be removed by contacting us at [info@VIDHIKARYA.com](mailto:info@VIDHIKARYA.com).

## Community Forums:

The Service may provide you the opportunity to participate and post content publicly in forums, on blogs, through interactive features VIDHIKARYA and through other communication functionality ("Community Forums"). You may choose, through such features or otherwise, to submit or post questions, comments, or other content. Please note that certain information, such as your name and Profile may be publicly displayed on the Service along with your User Forum Content. Please note that your use of Community Forums is subject to the VIDHIKARYA Forum Rules and our Terms of Service. Note that anything you post to a Community Forum is public -- others will have access to your User Forum Content and may use it or share it with third parties. If you choose to voluntarily disclose Personal Information in your User Forum Content or use Community Forums to link to your Profile, that information will be considered public information and the protections of this Privacy Policy will not apply.

## Testimonials:

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [info@VIDHIKARYA.com](mailto:info@VIDHIKARYA.com). Work Listings through the Service:

If you choose to post a legal matter listing via the Service as a Client/User, the contents of such listing will be viewable publicly.

## Feedback:

We collect feedback from VIDHIKARYA Users about their experience with other VIDHIKARYA Users of our Service. Please note that any feedback you provide via the Service or feedback provided about you is publicly viewable via the Service. On very rare occasions, we may remove feedback pursuant to our Feedback Removal Policy.

## Social Networking Services:

You may register to join the Service directly via the Service or by logging into your account with a third party social networking service (“SNS”) via our Service (e.g., Facebook, LinkedIn and other third party services that let you sign in using your existing credentials with those services). If you choose to register via an SNS, or to later link your account with the Service to your account with an SNS, we will use the Personal Information you have provided to the SNS (such as your name, email address, gender and other information you make publicly available via the SNS) to create your account. Note that the information we collect from and through an SNS may depend on the privacy settings you have set with the SNS and the permissions you grant to us in connection with linking your account with the Service to your account with an SNS. Other than what we may share with the SNS as described below, the Personal Information an SNS has about you is obtained by the SNS independent of our Service, and VIDHIKARYA is not responsible for it. The VIDHIKARYA Service also may permit additional interactions between it and a third party website, service, or other content provider, such as enabling you to “like” or share content to a third party SNS. If you choose to “like” or share content, or to otherwise share information from or via our Service with a third party site or service, that information may be publicly displayed, and the third party may have access to information about you and your use of our Service (and we may have access to information about you from that third party). These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interactions with third parties through SNS or similar features are governed by the respective privacy policies of those third parties.

## 2\. USE AND RETENTION OF INFORMATION

We use information we collect: To provide and improve the Service, complete your transactions, and address your inquiries, process your registration, verify the information you provide is valid and for compliance and internal business purposes;

To contact you with administrative communications and VIDHIKARYA newsletters, marketing or promotional materials (on behalf of VIDHIKARYA or third parties) and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please do let us know by sending a mail to policymatters @vidhikarya.com

Unless you request that we delete certain information (see Changing Your Information or Closing Your Account below), we retain the information we collect for at least 5 years and may retain the information for as long as needed for our business and legal purposes.

## 3\. INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE

We may share aggregated Non-Identifying Information and we may otherwise disclose Non-Identifying Information to third parties. We do not share your Personal Information with third parties for those third parties' marketing purposes unless we first provide you with the opportunity to opt-in to or opt-out of such sharing. We may also share the information we have collected about you, including Personal Information, as disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent, as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, or in the following circumstances:

Information about Lawyers Shared with Clients:

We share information regarding Lawyers working on a Client/User matter, including information in work history, with Clients. Note that if a Lawyer is suspended from the VIDHIKARYA Service, we may share that information with Clients for whom that Lawyer has worked or applied for work. If you choose to apply for work as a Lawyer via the Service, we will share information relevant to your application with the applicable Client(s), including, but not limited to, the information contained in your Lawyer Profile.

## Service Providers:

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and online advertising, payment processing, fraud detection and improvement of VIDHIKARYA’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. These third parties may have access to your Personal Information in order to perform these tasks on our behalf.

## Legal and Investigative Purposes:

VIDHIKARYA will share information with government agencies as required by law, including without limitation, in connection with reporting earnings. We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process, at the request of governmental authorities or other third parties conducting an investigation, to protect the property and rights of VIDHIKARYA or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, fraudulent, unethical or legally actionable activity. We may also use Device Identifiers to identify VIDHIKARYA Users, and may do so in cooperation with third parties at our discretion.

## Internal and Business Transfers:

VIDHIKARYA may share information, including Personal Information, with its other companies, subsidiaries, and affiliates, primarily for business and operational purposes. We may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets (including, in each case, as part of the due-diligence process with any potential acquiring entity) or in the event of bankruptcy. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

## 4\. THIRD PARTY ANALYTICS PROVIDERS AND SIMILAR THIRD PARTIES

VIDHIKARYA works with (or may in the future work with) network advertisers, ad agencies, analytics service providers and other vendors to provide us with information regarding traffic on the Service, including pages viewed and the actions taken when visiting the Service; to serve our advertisements on other web sites, within mobile apps and elsewhere online; and to provide us with information regarding the use of the Service and the effectiveness of our advertisements. Our service providers may collect certain information about your visits to and activity on the Service as well as other websites or services, they may set and access their own tracking technologies on your device, and may use that information to show you targeted advertisements. Some of these parties may collect Personal Information when you visit the Service or other online websites and services.

## 5\. YOUR CHOICES AND OPTING OUT

Registered VIDHIKARYA Users may update their choices regarding the types of communications you receive from us through your online account. You also may opt-out of receiving marketing emails from us by following the opt-out instructions provided in those emails. Registered VIDHIKARYA Users who access the Service by using a VIDHIKARYA mobile application may, with permission, receive push notifications. Notification preferences can be modified in the settings menu for the mobile application.

## 6\. CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION OR CLOSING YOUR ACCOUNT

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as your contact information, and you must update any changes through your online account. If you request to access all personal information you’ve submitted, we will respond to your request to access within 30 days. If you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated. If your account is deactivated or you ask to close your account, you will no longer be able to use the Service. If you would like us to delete your account in our system, you can do so by sending a mail to info @vidhikarya.com. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request; however, certain information will actively persist on the Service even if you close your account, including information in your Work and messages you posted to the Service. In addition, your Personal Information may remain in our archives and information you update or delete, or information within a closed account, may persist internally or for our administrative purposes. It is not always possible to completely remove or delete information from our databases. In addition, we typically will not remove information you posted publicly through or on the Service. Bear in mind that neither you nor VIDHIKARYA can delete all copies of information that has been previously shared with others on the Service.

## 7\. SECURITY

VIDHIKARYA takes commercially reasonable steps to help protect and secure the information it collects and stores about VIDHIKARYA Users. But remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Thus, while we strive to protect your personal data, VIDHIKARYA cannot ensure and does not warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.

## 8\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

VIDHIKARYA is an Indian company. If you are located outside the Union of India and choose to provide information to us, VIDHIKARYA transfers Personal Information to India for processing. India may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to the India, we will protect it as described in this Privacy Policy. By visiting the Service, or providing VIDHIKARYA with any information, you fully understand and unambiguously consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in India.

## 9\. LINKS TO OTHER SITES

Our Service may contain links to other websites. If you choose to click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website. The fact that we link to a website is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit Personal Information from you. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

## 10\. PHISHING

Phishing websites imitate legitimate websites in order to obtain personal or financial information. Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to VIDHIKARYA. If you believe you have received an email or had a similar interaction with a third party pretending to be VIDHIKARYA, please report it at [info@VIDHIKARYA.com](mailto:info@VIDHIKARYA.com).

## 11\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

VIDHIKARYA may update this Privacy Policy at any time and any changes will be effective upon posting. In the event that there are material changes to the way we treat your Personal Information, we will display a notice through the Services prior to the change becoming effective. We may also notify you by email, in our discretion. However, we will use your Personal Information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless you consent to the new or revised policy.

## 12\. CONTACTING US

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [policymatters@VIDHIKARYA.com](mailto:policymatters@VIDHIKARYA.com).
